[Current Processing Time: 2-4 Business Days + Time in Transit. Free shipping on most orders over $99!Click For Shipping Details](https://northwoodcandlesupply.com/pages/about-us)

* Fragrance Oils
    
    Fragrance Oils

    * Fragrance 1

        Fragrance 2

        Fragrance 3

        Fragrance 4

* Candle Making Supplies
    
    Candle Making Supplies

* Colorants
    
    Colorants
    
    * Shop By Color
        
        Shop By Color

* Craft Supplies
    
    Craft Supplies

* Fragrance Oils

    * Fragrance 1

        Fragrance 2

        Fragrance 3

        Fragrance 4

* Candle Making Supplies

* Colorants
    
    * Shop By Color

* Craft Supplies

Search

 Search [Log in](https://northwoodcandlesupply.com/customer_authentication/redirect?locale=en&region_country=US) [Favourites 0](https://northwoodcandlesupply.com/pages/wishlist "Favourites") [Shopping bag](https://northwoodcandlesupply.com/cart)

Item added to your cart
-----------------------

Check out

Continue shopping

[Home](https://northwoodcandlesupply.com/ "Back to the home page") | Privacy policy

Privacy policy
==============

Your Privacy is important to us. Basically - we don't share your personally identifiable information with anyone unless we have to. Unless you choose to opt out of cookies, some information may be used to customize your experience on this website and other sites on the internet. Thank you for your business.   
\----

SECTION 1 - WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION?

When you purchase something from our store, as part of the buying and selling process, we collect the personal information you give us such as your name, address and email address.  
When you browse our store, we also automatically receive your computer’s internet protocol (IP) address in order to provide us with information that helps us learn about your browser and operating system.  
Email marketing (if applicable): With your permission, we may send you emails about our store, new products and other updates.

SECTION 2 - CONSENT

How do you get my consent?  
When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order, arrange for a delivery or return a purchase, we imply that you consent to our collecting it and using it for that specific reason only.  
If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason, like marketing, we will either ask you directly for your expressed consent, or provide you with an opportunity to say no.

How do I withdraw my consent?  
If after you opt-in, you change your mind, you may withdraw your consent for us to contact you, for the continued collection, use or disclosure of your information, at anytime, by contacting us at brian@northwoodcandlecompany.com or mailing us at:  
NorthWood Candle Supply  
201 N Meridian St, Belle Plaine, MN 56011

SECTION 3 - DISCLOSURE

We may disclose your personal information if we are required by law to do so or if you violate our Terms of Service.

SECTION 4 - SHOPIFY

Our store is hosted on Shopify Inc. They provide us with the online e-commerce platform that allows us to sell our products and services to you.  
Your data is stored through Shopify’s data storage, databases and the general Shopify application. They store your data on a secure server behind a firewall.

Payment:  
If you choose a direct payment gateway to complete your purchase, then Shopify stores your credit card data. It is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is stored only as long as is necessary to complete your purchase transaction. After that is complete, your purchase transaction information is deleted.  
All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover.  
PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of credit card information by our store and its service providers.  
For more insight, you may also want to read Shopify’s Terms of Service (https://www.shopify.com/legal/terms) or Privacy Statement (https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy).

SECTION 5 - THIRD-PARTY SERVICES

In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us.  
However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.  
For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers.  
In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.  
As an example, if you are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the United States, then your personal information used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.  
Once you leave our store’s website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s Terms of Service.

With your permission, our website utilizes the Conversion Tracking Pixel of Facebook Inc, 1601 S. California Ave., Palo Alto CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). This tool allows user behavior to be tracked after they have been redirected to a provider’s website after clicking on a Facebook advertisement. This allows us to record the effectiveness of Facebook advertisements for statistical and market research purposes. The data collected is anonymous, meaning we cannot see the personal data of any individual user. However, the collected data are saved and processed by Facebook. Facebook is able to connect the data with your Facebook account and use the data for their own advertising purposes, in accordance with Facebook’s Data Use Policy: https://www.facebook.com/policy.php. You can allow Facebook and its partners to place ads on and off Facebook. A cookie may also be stored on your computer to serve these purposes. Facebook advertising preferences and data collection permissions can be changed here: https://www.facebook.com/adpreferences/ad\_settings/

Links  
When you click on links on our store, they may direct you away from our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements.

SECTION 6 - SECURITY

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.  
If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

SECTION 7 - COOKIES

Here is a list of cookies that we use. We’ve listed them here so you that you can choose if you want to opt-out of cookies or not.  
\_session\_id, unique token, sessional, Allows Shopify to store information about your session (referrer, landing page, etc).  
\_shopify\_visit, no data held, Persistent for 30 minutes from the last visit, Used by our website provider’s internal stats tracker to record the number of visits  
\_shopify\_uniq, no data held, expires midnight (relative to the visitor) of the next day, Counts the number of visits to a store by a single customer.  
cart, unique token, persistent for 2 weeks, Stores information about the contents of your cart.  
\_secure\_session\_id, unique token, sessional  
storefront\_digest, unique token, indefinite If the shop has a password, this is used to determine if the current visitor has access.

SECTION 8 - AGE OF CONSENT

By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this site.

SECTION 9 - CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.  
If our store is acquired or merged with another company, your information may be transferred to the new owners so that we may continue to sell products to you.

QUESTIONS AND CONTACT INFORMATION

If you would like to: access, correct, amend or delete any personal information we have about you, register a complaint, or simply want more information contact our Privacy Compliance Officer at brian@northwoodcandlecompany.com or by mail at  
NorthWood Candle Company  
\[Re: Privacy Compliance Officer\]  
201 N Meridian St, Belle Plaine, MN 56011

\----

We use a third-party service provider to serve ads and/or collect data on our behalf across the Internet and sometimes on this website. Some of these service providers may collect information about your visits to our website, and your interaction with our products and services to tailor marketing messages on this website and other sites or to trigger real time interaction, customize this Web site or enhance your profile. Some of these service providers may be able to collect personal information that you share with this site via a web form automatically and prior to your pressing a submit button; and they may be able to use information from your visits to this site to send marketing messages to you in a way that may personally identify you. This information is collected through the use of a cookie, a javascript tag and/or pixel, which is industry standard technology used by most major web sites. The information collected by these service providers may include your device's IP address, user agent, email addresses (where hashed or otherwise rendered pseudonymous) and other user and device level pseudonymous information. Please keep in mind that your browser settings may not permit you to control the technologies utilized by these third-party companies. If you would like more information about these practices, please click: [http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/.)

Subscribe to our newsletter!
----------------------------

 Email

TOP COLLECTIONS
---------------

INFORMATION
-----------

POLICIES
--------

ABOUT US
--------

NorthWood Distributing is a family-owned candle supply company that carries top-quality supplies for making candles, soap, wax melts, bath bombs & more.

[Read our story here](https://northwoodcandlesupply.com/pages/our-story "Our Story")!

© 2024, [NorthWood Distributing](https://northwoodcandlesupply.com/)[](https://www.shopify.com/?utm_campaign=poweredby&utm_medium=shopify&utm_source=onlinestore)

* Choosing a selection results in a full page refresh.
* Opens in a new window.

0

Add to Compare Clear all

You have added the maximum of products to compare.
